ARSENE DEMENOU

+237 653 522 435 | demenoucompassion02@gmail.com | Douala, Cameroon https://www.linkedin.com/in/arsene-demenou | https://gdac.vercel.app

WEB DEVELOPER

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

An organised and dependable Full Stack Web developer with two years of experience, successful at managing multiple priorities. Have worked on multi-vendor ecommerce web applications with payment API integration and on dynamic video games. Enthusiastic with a perfectionist mind working on both desktop and mobile projects and on the lookout for new opportunities to put my experience to work for the company's development.

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer Striving For All, Douala - Cameroon

01/2024 - 06/2024

- Designed and updated website layouts to meet usability and performance requirements.
- Developed web applications to improve on the sale performances and boost marketing strategies.
- Improved graphic tools to boost user interaction and deliver design versatility, with tools such as Illustrator, Canva and Photoshop.

IT Consultant 11/2022 - 01/2024

JGME Consulting, Douala - Cameroon

- Met with clients to understand business requirements, performed gap analysis and translated technical requirements.
- Developed web applications, reviewed and tested plans and criteria to meet functional and technical requirements.
- Enhanced project management skills by defining and presenting system solutions and timelines for business needs or technical problems.
- Developed diagrams, data dictionaries to describe and lay out logical operational steps.

Web Developer & UI designer Freelance

09/2022 - Current

- eelance
- Developed application's user interfaces via emerging front-end technologies like ReactJs.
- Worked with designed teams, project managers and business analysts to create intuitive and easy-to-use UI designs.
- Design video game interfaces and develop automation programs in JavaScript using the ThreeJS tool.
- Communicated with product managers and UX designers to fine-tune interfaces and improve user experience.

Frontend Web Developer Stillforce Technologies, Douala - Cameroon

09/2020 - 01/2021

- Developed application's user interfaces via emerging technologies such as Laravel and Vue.Js
- Worked with designed teams, project managers and business analysts to create intuitive and easy-to-use software.

- Worked closely with UX and product teams to define visual and functional requirements.
- Communicated with product managers and Backend developers to build and configure the database according to the project requirements, with API integrations like Google map, PayPal.

SKILLS

[Creativity] | [Adaptability] | [Communication] | [Attention to detail] | [Time Management] | [Leadership]

Programming Languages: HTML5, CSS, Python, JavaScript, PHP, C++, JAVA, Typescript

Frameworks: React.js, Laravel, Tailwind CSS, React Native, ThreeJS, NodeJS, Vue.JS, Next.js

Dev & Management Tools: Git, DialogFlow, Firebase, Power BI, JIRA, DOCKER, AWS

CMS: WordPress

Graphic Tools: Figma, Canva, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology in **Software Engineering**

July / 2022

Institut Universitaire de la Côte, Douala

A one-year professional training (continuity to HND) with an annual gpa score of 3.12 on a scale of 4. Have defended an end of year tech project on "A web Chabot Application" with an excellent grade.

Higher National Diploma in Software Engineering

July / 2021

Institut Universitaire de la Côte, Douala

A two-year professional training with an annual gpa score of 3.3 on a scale of 4. Have defended an end of year tech project which was carried on "Development of a Website for road and building monitoring" with a very good grade.

CERTIFICATIONS

- [C++ Programming], [FREECODECAMP] [2024]
- [Python Programming], [SOLOLEARN] [2022]
- [PHP Programming], [SOLOLEARN] [2022]
- [ReactJS & Redux Programming], [Great Learning] [2024]
- **[GitHub]**, [Microsoft] 2023

AWARDS/RECOGNITIONS/VOLUNTEER WORK

• E-commerce website Integration with Odoo ERP (V16)

August 2023